# Jason O'Dell

Chapel Hill, NC jasoneodell@gmail.com (336) 403-7837 Portfolio

## **Summary**

I'm a full stack developer with five years of experience in both web and mobile development. In my current position over the last four years I've focused on the Django clinician web portal and Flutter mobile app. While working as a developer on a smaller team at a startup, I gained lots of experience owning products and implementing many features while working both collaboratively and independently. This position encouraged a great deal of flexibility and I learned many new technologies while working across the entire stack.

# **Work Experience**

VitalFlo Oct 2020 - Present

Full-Stack Developer

- Built the frontend of our clinician portal nearly from scratch by redesigning and implementing 20+ new features including alerts, billing, trends, reports, etc.
- Reviewed and provided feedback for ~150 pull requests
- Completed an average of 7 Jira cards per week
- Squashed 198 bugs
- Collaborated with Product Team to create Product Requirements Documents for all feature development
- Rebuilt patient population page to reduce page load time by 65% for larger clients
- Learned Flutter and took over development for our mobile app while implementing 5+ new features including trends, pre/post testing, Awair integration, etc.

#### Freelance Developer

Sept 2019 - Present

Boone UAS Drones (https://www.booneuasdrones.com)

- Built business portfolio website for drone services business using React and Next.js Brianna Haferman Photography (https://www.briannahaferman.com)
  - Built creative media portfolio website using React and Next.js

Piedmont Legacy Trails (https://plt-blueways-map.vercel.app/)

 Built interactive river/paddle access points map for 12 county region of North Carolina using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and MapBox

WordPress Developer

Designed WordPress websites for holiday lights business and podiatry firm

#### **Ekren Construction LLC**

Dec 2017 - Aug 2018

Carpentry Apprentice

 Assisted in various carpentry projects such as deck-building, framing, structural repair, kitchen/bathroom remodeling, etc

### **Signal Mountain Lodge**

May 2017 - Oct 2017

Cook

- Prepared ingredients and worked the line as a cook during my seasonal job in Grand Teton National Park
- Hiked 250+ miles of beautiful mountain terrain

#### Larry O'Dell CPA, PC

May 2015 - May 2017

Bookkeeper

 Managed financial transactions and filed taxes for 25+ local businesses using QuickBooks and Drake

# **Personal Projects**

### Wedding App

 We wanted to have an app for our wedding which included an interactive Bingo game, quiz about us, and itinerary so I built one using Flutter

#### **Spotify New Releases**

• Before Spotify had the "What's New" feature, I wanted to see all new releases from my followed artists so I built a web app to login via OAuth and display your new releases

### Codebreaker

• I wanted to play around with the OpenAI API and we play the board game Codenames often so I built a Flutter app to screenshot the game board, send your words to OpenAI, then request the best ways to link the words together for clues

# <u>Technical Skills, Languages, and Systems</u>

- HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Javascript, React, Dart, Flutter
- Python, Django, Node.js, PostgreSQL
- Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jenkins
- AWS
- WordPress, Webflow, Mapbox, Tableau

## **Education**

## **NC State University**

- Computer Programming Certificate, 2019-2020
- Bachelor of Science, Human Biology, 2011-2015